<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nicole Orchard</title>
    <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nicole Orchard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="nicoleorchard.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TechEd Consortium</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/tec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/tec/</guid>
      <description>Logo and illustrations done at Division Of/ for the website of the Technology for Education Consortium, which is working to improve technology purchasing in schools. The illustrations depict their commitment to fixing problems in efficiency, efficacy, and transparency.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Reuse</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/big-reuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/big-reuse/</guid>
      <description>Logo design for the rebranding of an awesome recycling company based in Brooklyn and Queens. Learn more about Big Reuse .
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kulen Outreach</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/kulen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/kulen/</guid>
      <description>Really fun branding and web design project with the Division Of/ team for a non-profit running schools in Cambodia. The project won a Communicator Award in the Corporate Identity - Logo category. The logo was inspired by the iconic architecture of Ankor Wat. I was lucky enough to see the signage in person while traveling in Cambodia. You can learn more about Kulen and check out the website design at kulenoutreach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cockroach Labs</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/cockroach-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/cockroach-labs/</guid>
      <description>I worked with the Division Of/ team on everything from marketing collateral including swag like stickers and hats, posters and other print media for events, as well as the main product website design and forum page styling for the new database startup Cockroach Labs .
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minesweeper</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/minesweeper/minesweeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/minesweeper/minesweeper/</guid>
      <description>As a kid I could spend hours playing this game, so it was an especially fun first React project. Try not to blow up the animals! (Hint: double click to lock mines in place 🔒). If you ever get tired of playing, take a look at the code .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC Public Art</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/nycpublicart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/nycpublicart/</guid>
      <description>I made this website to visually explore temporary art exhibits around New York in a digital interface. I used D3 to plot the coordinates of temporary public art exhibits in NYC on a map, loading exhibit information and dynamically fetching an image for each. The static site is hosted on AWS S3. The original architecture for this project ran a Ruby script via a weekly cronjob to update the dataset on Monday mornings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>