<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicole Orchard</title>
    <link>nicoleorchard.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nicole Orchard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="nicoleorchard.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TechEd Consortium</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/tec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/tec/</guid>
      <description>Logo and illustrations done at Division Of/ for the website of the Technology for Education Consortium, which is working to improve technology purchasing in schools. The illustrations depict their commitment to fixing problems in efficiency, efficacy, and transparency.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Reuse</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/big-reuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/big-reuse/</guid>
      <description>Logo design for the rebranding of an awesome recycling company based in Brooklyn and Queens. Learn more about Big Reuse .
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kulen Outreach</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/kulen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/kulen/</guid>
      <description>Really fun branding and web design project with the Division Of/ team for a non-profit running schools in Cambodia. The project won a Communicator Award in the Corporate Identity - Logo category. The logo was inspired by the iconic architecture of Ankor Wat. I was lucky enough to see the signage in person while traveling in Cambodia. You can learn more about Kulen and check out the website design at kulenoutreach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cockroach Labs</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/cockroach-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/cockroach-labs/</guid>
      <description>I worked with the Division Of/ team on everything from marketing collateral including swag like stickers and hats, posters and other print media for events, as well as the main product website design and forum page styling for the new database startup Cockroach Labs .
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to Compilers</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-08-13-compilers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-08-13-compilers/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: Learning new meanings for front-end and back-end .
A compiler is just a program that translates other programs. Traditional compilers translate source code into executable machine code that your computer understands. (Some compilers translate source code into another programming language. These compilers are called source-to-source translators or transpilers.) LLVM is a widely used compiler project, consisting of many modular compiler tools.
Traditional compiler design comprises three parts:  The Frontend translates source code into an intermediate representation (IR)*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Managers</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-06-22-package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-06-22-package-managers/</guid>
      <description>If you want to draw for the first time, someone might hand you a piece of paper and a pencil. They won&amp;rsquo;t spend time discussing where the paper and pencil came from. Instead, they&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about line, form, and negative space. If you want to write a Python program for the first time, someone might run the following commands on your machine:
$ apt install python3 $ pip3 install ipython Then they would open iPython and show you some basic Python syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should I Work On?</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-05-23-what-should-i-work-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-05-23-what-should-i-work-on/</guid>
      <description>Last year I was a web designer with a time-consuming programming pastime. In August I left my job to travel and study full-time. This post is about what I learned from nine months of self-study and the resources I used.
Bootcamps might not be for you Bootcamps are great for people with financial resources who want to dive into web development without previous technical experience. I opted out of doing a bootcamp for three reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I built this website using the Hugo static site generator. It is hosted on GitHub pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friends</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/friends/</guid>
      <description>Some of the many people in my life whose work I admire:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minesweeper</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/minesweeper/minesweeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/minesweeper/minesweeper/</guid>
      <description>As a kid I could spend hours playing this game, so it was an especially fun first React project. Try not to blow up the animals! (Hint: double click to lock mines in place 🔒). If you ever get tired of playing, take a look at the code .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC Public Art</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/projects/nycpublicart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/projects/nycpublicart/</guid>
      <description>I made this website to visually explore temporary art exhibits around New York in a digital interface. I used D3 to plot the coordinates of temporary public art exhibits in NYC on a map, loading exhibit information and dynamically fetching an image for each. The static site is hosted on AWS S3. The original architecture for this project ran a Ruby script via a weekly cronjob to update the dataset on Monday mornings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>