<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Nicole Orchard</title>
    <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Nicole Orchard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="nicoleorchard.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to Compilers</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-08-13-compilers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-08-13-compilers/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: Learning new meanings for front-end and back-end .
A compiler is just a program that translates other programs. Traditional compilers translate source code into executable machine code that your computer understands. (Some compilers translate source code into another programming language. These compilers are called source-to-source translators or transpilers.) LLVM is a widely used compiler project, consisting of many modular compiler tools.
Traditional compiler design comprises three parts:  The Frontend translates source code into an intermediate representation (IR)*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Managers</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-06-22-package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-06-22-package-managers/</guid>
      <description>If you want to draw for the first time, someone might hand you a piece of paper and a pencil. They won&amp;rsquo;t spend time discussing where the paper and pencil came from. Instead, they&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about line, form, and negative space. If you want to write a Python program for the first time, someone might run the following commands on your machine:
$ apt install python3 $ pip3 install ipython Then they would open iPython and show you some basic Python syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should I Work On?</title>
      <link>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-05-23-what-should-i-work-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>nicoleorchard.com/blog/2017-05-23-what-should-i-work-on/</guid>
      <description>Last year I was a web designer with a time-consuming programming pastime. In August I left my job to travel and study full-time. This post is about what I learned from nine months of self-study and the resources I used.
Bootcamps might not be for you Bootcamps are great for people with financial resources who want to dive into web development without previous technical experience. I opted out of doing a bootcamp for three reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>